Guide to the University of Chicago Department of Botany Records 1882-1972
University of Chicago Library
- Series VI: Photographs, circa 1891-1936
  - Subseries 7: Lantern Slides
    - Wisconsin, AEP-WIS1, Second growth of Populus tremuloides two stages after burns west of Bayfield, Wisconsin AEP-WIS2, Tsuga canadensis, Acer saccharinum, and Betula lutea in the Siskiwit forest, Bayfield, Wisconsin AEP-WIS3, The forests of Bayfield, Wisconsin AEP-WIS4, Sandstone arches on Lake Superior at the eastern shore of Madeline Island near Bayfield, Wisconsin AEP-WIS5, Drumlin near Columbus, Wisconsin AEP-WIS6, Maple seedling in a climax forest, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS7, Maple seedling in a climax forest, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS8, Maple seedling in a climax forest, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS9, A circle of Betula papyrifera, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS10, A circle of Betula papyrifera, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS11, Fraxinus swamp, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS12, Fraxinus swamp with Iris between shrubs and trees, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS13, Habenaria orbiculata, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS14, Dwarf Larix, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS15, Witches Broom on Juniperus horizontalis, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS16, Witches Broom on Juniperus horizontalis, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS17, Lake Michigan levels on Door Bluff, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS18, A rising shoreline on Lake Michigan, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS19, A gravel island and rising shoreline on Lake Michigan, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS20, Maple seedling in a conifer forest, Carlsens Woods, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS21, Henry Chandler Cowles of the University of Chicago Department of Botany in a cave at present Lake Michigan level, Ellison Bay, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS22, A rising shoreline on Lake Michigan at Europe Bay, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS23, Betula papyrifera, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS24, The moss Grimmia, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS25, Thuja and the moss Grimmia, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS26, Garret Bay Inn, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS27, Garret Bay Inn, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS28, Thuja occidentalis, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS29, Moss succession, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS30, Moss succession, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS31, Thuja, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS32, A fish stake of Ash sprouting leaves, Garret Bay, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS33, A rising shoreline on Lake Michigan, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS34, A beach strewn with shingle, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS35, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS36, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS37, Terrace and cliff, Garret Bay, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS38, Witches Broom on Juniperus horizontalis, Moonlight Bay, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS39, Dr. Warren Gookin Waterman and Erling Christophersen, Europe Lake, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS40, Pinus resinosa, Europe Lake, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS41, Henry Chandler Cowles and a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS42, Henry Chandler Cowles and a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS43, Esther Wade on a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class trip, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS44, A University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class, Garret Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS45, May Theilgaard propelling Henry Chandler Cowles about Big Bay, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS46, Henry Chandler Cowles and a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class, Moonlight Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS47, U. S. Mail boat, the Lusitania, Presque Isle to Old Mission, Apostle Islands, Wisconsin AEP-WIS48, Henry Chandler Cowles and a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class under Pinus resinosa, Big Bay, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS49, Picea with and without Witches Broom, Moonlight Bay, Wisconsin AEP-WIS50, Spruce weakened by Witches Broom and killed by Dwarf Mistletoe, Moonlight Bay, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS51, Juniperus horizontalis in a pasture, Newport, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS52, Spruce killed by Dwarf Mistletoe, Moonlight Bay, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS53, Flora of emerging terrace, New Port State Park, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS54, Flora of emerging terrace, New Port State Park, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS55, A rising Lake Michigan shoreline with driftwood, New Port State Park, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS56, Rising Lake Michigan shoreline, New Port State Park, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS57, Henry Chandler Cowles of the University of Chicago Department of Botany standing next to lichen on a north-facing fence, Rowley Bay, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS58, A south-facing fence at Rowley Bay, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS59, New Port State Park, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS60, Betula lutea on a Tsuga canadensis, Washington Island, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS61, Acer saccharum in a forest habitat, Washington Island, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS62, Betula lutea on a Tsuga canadensis, Washington Island, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS63, Washington Island, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS64, Washington Island, Door County, Wisconsin AEP-WIS65, Field of Hollandex, Kenosha, Wisconsin AEP-WIS66, A kettle hole lake, Wisconsin AEP-WIS67, The killing of trees by artificial flooding, Kilbourn, Wisconsin AEP-WIS68, The killing of trees by artificial flooding, Kilbourn, Wisconsin AEP-WIS70, Dam at Mirror Lake near Kilbourn, Wisconsin AEP-WIS71, Wave cut shelf slightly above normal water level, Presque Isle, Wisconsin AEP-WIS72, Wave cut shelf, Presque Isle, Wisconsin AEP-WIS73, Transition from Ammophila dune to conifer forest at the south end of Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS74, Pure stand of Pinus resinosa at the end of Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS75, A Pinus resinosa, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS76, Erosion of an old sand bar, Big Bay, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS77, Shoreline of Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS78, Shoreline at the south end of Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS79, Remnant of a Pinus resinosa forest on a sand bar, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS80, A Pinus strobus with an unusual number of cones, La Pointe, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS81, The mouth of a drowned river north of Old Mission, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS82, Floating islands, Big Bay Lake, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS83, Floating islands with Carex filiformis in the foreground, Big Bay Lake, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS84, Logs in the mouth of a drowned river north of Old Mission, Madeline Island, Wisconsin AEP-WIS85, Elm, Pine, and Oak in a young valley of the Little Platte River, Platteville, Wisconsin AEP-WIS86, Polyporus, Platteville, Wisconsin AEP-WIS87, Pinus strobus fruit, Stevens Point, Wisconsin AEP-WIS88, Thuja occidentalis fruit, Stevens Point, Wisconsin AEP-WIS89, Erosion on a hillside, Stevens Point, Wisconsin AEP-WIS90, Pinus resinosa, Wisconsin AEP-WIS91, Erosion along the shore of a small lake, Wisconsin AEP-WIS92, Erosion along the shore of a small lake, Wisconsin AEP-WIS93, Eroding bluff of a small lake tenanted by trees, Wisconsin AEP-WIS94, Erosion in Wisconsin at Grabers Slide AEP-WIS95, Contrast between eroded and tree covered areas, Wisconsin AEP-WIS96, A fertile Wisconsin valley ruined by boulders washed down in a freshet AEP-WIS97, Sediment in a cornfield due to one storm, Wisconsin AEP-WIS98, Sunset in Wisconsin AEP-WIS103, A monadnock, Camp Douglas, Wisconsin AEP-WIS108, A sandstone river bluff, Dells of Wisconsin, Kilbourn, Wisconsin (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 27)
    - Wyoming, AEP-WYS2, Opuntia sp., Cody, Wyoming AEP-WYS6, A road in Shoshone Canyon, Wyoming AEP-WYS9, Apocynum androsaemifolium, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS10, Artemisia tridentata, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS11, Artemisia tridentata, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS12, Abies invading Pinus murrayana, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS13, Abies invading Pinus murrayana, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS14, Abies invading Pinus murrayana, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS15, The result of snow and wind action on Abies lasiocarpa, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS16, The result of snow action on Abies lasiocarpa, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS17, Cerastium, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS18, Cleome glabra, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS19, Hypopitys multiflora, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS20, Juniperus communis, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS21, Lewisia rediviva, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS22, Machaeranthera bigelovii, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS23, Nymphaea polysepala, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS24, Pachylophis caespitosus, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS25, Picea engelmannii, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS26, Pinus flexilis, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS27, Pinus murrayana, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS28, Pinus murrayana, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS29, Pinus murrayana and pioneers Artemisia filifolia, Chrysopsis, and Eriogonum on an old geyser field, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS30, Pyrola uliginosa, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS32, George Damon Fuller of the University of Chicago Department of Botany and an unidentified woman standing next to fossil trees, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS33, George Damon Fuller of the University of Chicago Department of Botany standing next to a fossil tree, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS34, Angel Terrace, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS36, Camp Roosevelt, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS37, Lake camp, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS38, Devils Kitchen, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS41, Gardner River Canyon, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS42, A basalt cliff, Gardner River Canyon, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS44, Giant Geyser cone, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS46, Golden Gate, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS47, Grand Canyon of the Yellowstone with lower falls in the distance, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS48, Grand Canyon of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS49, Grand Canyon of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS50, A geyser, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS51, A "hat" geyser, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS52, Jupiter Terrace, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS53, Jupiter Terrace, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS54, Lone Star Geyser, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS55, Lone Star Geyser, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS56, Mallard Lake, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS57, Terraces at Mammoth Hot Springs, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS58, Mound Terrace, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS59, Orange Geyser, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS60, Riverside Geyser, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS61, Silver Gate, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS62, The Tea Kettle, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS63, Upper falls of the Yellowstone, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS65, A lake in Yellowstone, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS66, A meandering creek, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS67, A river meander in arid grassland, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS68, A terrace, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS69, A woodchuck, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS70, Buffalo in a corral, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS71, Petrified trees, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS72, Lupinus, Mt. Washburn, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS73, Phlox, Mt. Washburn, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS74, Pinus albicaulis, Mt. Washburn, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS75, Pinus albicaulis, Mt. Washburn, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS76, Pinus albicaulis wind timber, Mt. Washburn, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS77, Mt. Washburn wind timber, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS78, Mt. Washburn, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS79, Two Needle Pinyon with Mistletoe standing in Sagebrush, Wyoming AEP-WYS80, Pinus albicaulis wind timber, Mt. Washburn, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS81, Students of a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class watching a geyser, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS82, Students of a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS83, Mrs. William Cribbs feeding a hungry bear cub, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS84, A University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class in autos, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS85, In Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS86, A geyser, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS87, In Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS88, George Damon Fuller and students of a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class in Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS89, George Damon Fuller and students of a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class in Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS91, The International Congress of Plant Sciences Western Field Trip, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS92, Alice Peterson holding Elk antlers on a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class trip, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS93, Dr. Merriam standing next to petrified trees, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS94, Helen Dwyer and Alice Peterson, members of a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class at Giant Geyser, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS95, Students of a University of Chicago Department of Botany Field Ecology class in an old stagecoach, Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming AEP-WYS96, Dr. Frank Thone and Alice Peterson, Wyoming AEP-WYS97, High plains east of the Laramie Mountains, Wyoming (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawers 27-28)
  - Subseries 8: Unsorted Photographs
    - Lantern slides, Canada (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 29)
    - Lantern slides, Unidentified locations, probably Hawaii (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 30)
    - Lantern slides, Unidentified plants and sites (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 31)
    - Lantern slides, Unidentified trees and landforms (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 32)
    - Lantern slides, Canada (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 33)
    - Lantern slides, Canada (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 34)
    - Lantern slides, Canada (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 35)
    - Lantern slides, Mexico (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 36)
    - Lantern slides, Mexico Caribbean South America (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 37)
    - Lantern slides, Europe (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 38)
    - Lantern slides, Europe (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 39)
    - Lantern slides, Europe (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 40)
    - Lantern slides, Africa (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 41)
    - Lantern slides, Ceylon China India Japan (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 42)
    - Lantern slides, Australia Fiji Java New Guinea New Zealand (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 43)
    - Lantern slides, Philippines Samoa Tasmania Other foreign locations (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 44)
    - Lantern slides, Maps (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 45)
    - Lantern slides, History of botany, portraits of scientists (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 46)
    - Lantern slides, Mushroom experiments (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 47)
    - Lantern slides, Tree cross-sections Cellular diagrams (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 48)
    - Lantern slides, Diagrams (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 49)
    - Lantern slides, Graphs and charts (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 50)
    - Lantern slides, Diseases of trees Food production (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 51)
    - Lantern slides, Crop diseases (Box CABINET 1, Folder Drawer 52)
    - Group at Crater Lake, International Phytogeographic Excursion (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Carl Schroter, University of Zurich (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - George D. Fuller (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Yellowstone National Park (Box 64, Folder 4-5)
    - Barrington Bay, Nova Scotia (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Colorado (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Wychwood (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified, probably Wychwood (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Bird Haven (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Maps (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Individuals, plants and landforms (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Plants and landforms (Box 64, Folder 13-14)
    - Plants and landforms (Box 65, Folder 1-6)
    - American Environmental Photographs, 1891-1936, publicity images, Dune Park, Indiana, film negatives Henry C. Cowles, film negatives Colorado, glass plate negatives Indiana, glass plate negatives Various subjects, prints Various subjects, film negatives (Box 66, Folder 1-7)
    - Wychwood, portfolios and loose print (Box 67)
    - Bird Haven, albums (Box 67)